<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml><records><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Grochulska-Salak, Magdalena</author><author>Zielonko-Jung, Katarzyna</author><author>Zinowiec-Cieplik, Kinga</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>KSZTAŁTOWANIE ZABUDOWY I SYSTEMÓW ZIELENI NA TERENACH MIEJSKICH</title><secondary-title>PRACE NAUKOWE UNIWERSYTETU EKONOMICZNEGO WE WROCŁAWIU</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>PRACE NAUKOWE UNIWERSYTETU EKONOMICZNEGO WE WROCŁAWIU</full-title></periodical><pages>54-63</pages><dates><year>2018</year><pub-dates><date>2018</date></pub-dates></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.15611/pn.2018.504.05</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Dynamika wzrostu miast i problemy jakości ich środowiska skłaniają do badań nad możliwościami tworzenia efektywnych użytkowo systemów zieleni zintegrowanej</abstract><remote-database-name>mostwiedzy.pl</remote-database-name><language>polski</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://mostwiedzy.pl/pl/publication/ksztaltowanie-zabudowy-i-systemow-zieleni-na-terenach-miejskich,146892-1</url></web-urls><pdf-urls><url>C:\Users\Kuba\Zotero\storage\LJBYTTAD\Grochulska-Salak et al. - 2018 - KSZTAŁTOWANIE ZABUDOWY I SYSTEMÓW ZIELENI NA TEREN.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><access-date>2023-01-17 08:01:28</access-date></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Poćwierz, Marta</author><author>Zielonko-Jung, Katarzyna</author><author>Jędrzejewski, Mateusz</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>The problem of airflow around building clusters in different configurations</title><secondary-title>Archive of Mechanical Engineering; 2017; vol. 64; No 3; 401-418</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Archive of Mechanical Engineering; 2017; vol. 64; No 3; 401-418</full-title></periodical><keywords><keyword>airflow around buildings</keyword><keyword>CFD simulation</keyword><keyword>damage mechanics</keyword><keyword>environmental wind engineering</keyword><keyword>Nauki Techniczne</keyword><keyword>RSM model of turbulence</keyword><keyword>the k-ε realizable model of turbulence</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year><pub-dates><date>2017</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>0004-0738, E-ISSN 2300-1895</isbn><remote-database-name>dLibra</remote-database-name><urls><web-urls><url>https://journals.pan.pl/dlibra/publication/119817/edition/104249</url></web-urls><pdf-urls><url>C:\Users\Kuba\Zotero\storage\IS7TDIYU\Poćwierz et al. - 2017 - The problem of airflow around building clusters in.pdf</url></pdf-urls><text-urls><url>C:\Users\Kuba\Zotero\storage\PBKB69XA\content.html</url></text-urls></urls><access-date>2023-01-17 08:04:14</access-date></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Wicht, Marzena</author><author>Osińska-Skotak, Katarzyna</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Temporal analysis of urban changes and development in Warsaw’s ventilation corridors</title><secondary-title>Miscellanea Geographica</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Miscellanea Geographica</full-title></periodical><pages>11-21</pages><volume>20</volume><number>4</number><issue>4</issue><dates><year>2016</year><pub-dates><date>2016/12/01</date></pub-dates></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1515/mgrsd-2016-0021</electronic-resource-num><abstract>AbstractThis paper presents the results of the urban indicators analysis conducted within Warsaw’s ventilation corridors from 1992 to 2011. The literature review shows that the Floor Area Ratio (FAR) index is one of the best indicators to detect urban development; therefore, this was the core of the analysis. Three periods were analysed (1992 – 2002 – 2011), as such a long time-span allows the assumption that change will be visible. The ventilation corridors were divided into 500 m and 100 m grids and the FAR index was calculated for each cell. The results highlight alarming changes within some of the corridors, indicating areas that are crucial to sufficient air flow in Warsaw.</abstract><remote-database-name>sciendo.com</remote-database-name><language>en</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://sciendo.com/article/10.1515/mgrsd-2016-0021</url></web-urls><pdf-urls><url>C:\Users\Kuba\Zotero\storage\RQ7PZHTX\Wicht i Osińska-Skotak - 2016 - of urban changes and development in Warsaw’s venti.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><access-date>2023-01-17 08:05:00</access-date></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Wicht, Marzena</author><author>Wicht, Andreas</author><author>Osińska-Skotak, Katarzyna</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Detection of ventilation corridors using a spatio-temporal approach aided by remote sensing data</title><secondary-title>European Journal of Remote Sensing</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>European Journal of Remote Sensing</full-title></periodical><pages>254-267</pages><volume>50</volume><number>1</number><issue>1</issue><keywords><keyword>3D building database</keyword><keyword>frontal area index</keyword><keyword>roughness parameters</keyword><keyword>urban climate</keyword><keyword>ventilation corridors</keyword><keyword>done</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year><pub-dates><date>2017-01-01</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>NULL</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1080/22797254.2017.1318672</electronic-resource-num><abstract>The aim of this study is to detect ventilation corridors in three epochs (1992, 2002 and 2011) by mapping rough urban areas. The roughness parameters calculations are based on a 3D building database obtained from satellite imagery (SPOT) for thee epochs and are conducted accordingly to morphometric methods. Several ventilation paths are clearly recognisable for all three decades and based on the proximity analysis and roughness parameters (by calculating roughness length (z0) and zero-plane displacement height (zd)), we established their extent and analysed the structural and developmental changes. We conducted that changes occurred more rapidly in the second period – almost 90% of the study area was gradually built up, what obstructs the air flow. In addition, winds are blocked in the western part of the city – where the best wind conditions occur. The results urge to re-evaluate the current shape of ventilation corridors and suggest some new areas that should be included in the air ventilation system to improve citizens’ comfort and urban climate.</abstract><remote-database-name>Taylor and Francis+NEJM</remote-database-name><urls><web-urls><url>https://doi.org/10.1080/22797254.2017.1318672</url></web-urls><pdf-urls><url>C:\Users\Kuba\Zotero\storage\CVAHRX74\Wicht et al. - 2017 - Detection of ventilation corridors using a spatio-.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><access-date>2023-01-17 08:05:54</access-date></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Zielonko-Jung, Katarzyna</author><author>Janiak, Justyna</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Trees as a solar control measure for southern-oriented street frontages. Analysis of a selected street model for a humid continental climate</title><secondary-title>Urban Ecosystems</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Urban Ecosystems</full-title><abbr-1>Urban Ecosyst</abbr-1></periodical><pages>111-119</pages><volume>25</volume><number>1</number><issue>1</issue><keywords><keyword>Shading</keyword><keyword>Solar radiation</keyword><keyword>Street canyon</keyword><keyword>Sustainable planning</keyword><keyword>Trees</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2022</year><pub-dates><date>2022-02-01</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>1573-1642</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1007/s11252-021-01128-0</electronic-resource-num><abstract>The present study is aimed at the analysis of possibilities for shading southern frontage of street oriented along the E-W axis by the single row of trees, parallel to the southern elevations. The effectiveness of solar control shading was tested depending on the geometric relationships between trees and buildings. Numerical simulation analyses were conducted in Rhinoceros® program for the street located in humid continental climate in city Płock, Poland (52°32′50 “N 19°42’00 “E), for the day of the highest degree of total solar radiation in the year i.e. June 7th, during hours: 8.00a.m - 5.00 p.m. The analysis has proved that a row of 20–25 year old Sycamore Maple ‘Rotterdam’ in the street 30 m wide and 18 m high (H/W = 0.6), can provide solar protection for the southern frontage, especially when trees are located no more than 4 m away. Location of greenery within the range of 4 to 5 m from the buildings leads to a radical reduction in the possibility of shading the wall surfaces (at 5 m to 0%). Over 90% of the shading area of the ground floor façade walls was found when trees were within the distance 2 and 3 m away from the building.</abstract><remote-database-name>Springer Link</remote-database-name><language>en</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11252-021-01128-0</url></web-urls><pdf-urls><url>C:\Users\Kuba\Zotero\storage\UKQUDA59\Zielonko-Jung i Janiak - 2022 - Trees as a solar control measure for southern-orie.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><access-date>2023-01-17 08:06:35</access-date></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Web Page">12</ref-type><titles><title>Niewielu wie o ich istnieniu. Sprawdź, co zapewniają kliny napowietrzające</title><secondary-title>Informacje i aktualności z rynku nieruchomości</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Informacje i aktualności z rynku nieruchomości</full-title></periodical><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023-01-17 08:06:45</date></pub-dates></dates><abstract>Niewielu mieszkańców Warszawy zdaje sobie sprawę z faktu, że życie w stolicy jest bardziej znośne dzięki ciekawej obserwacji urbanistów poczynionej ponad 100 lat temu. Zauważyli bowiem, że do funkcjonowania dużych aglomeracji niezbędne są tzw. kliny napowietrzające. W Warszawie jest ich dziewięć. Jaka jest ich funkcja?</abstract><language>pl</language><urls><web-urls><url>http://www.domiporta.pl/informacje/a/niewielu-wie-o-ich-istnieniu-sprawdz-co-zapewniaja-kliny-napowietrzajace-5114</url></web-urls></urls><access-date>2023-01-17 08:06:45</access-date></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Gu, Kangkang</author><author>Fang, Yunhao</author><author>Qian, Zhao</author><author>Sun, Zhen</author><author>Wang, Ai</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Spatial planning for urban ventilation corridors by urban climatology</title><secondary-title>Ecosystem Health and Sustainability</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Ecosystem Health and Sustainability</full-title></periodical><pages>1747946</pages><volume>6</volume><number>1</number><issue>1</issue><keywords><keyword>heat island intensity</keyword><keyword>urban climatology</keyword><keyword>Ventilation corridors</keyword><keyword>ventilation potential</keyword><keyword>wind environment</keyword><keyword>don</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2020</year><pub-dates><date>2020-12-16</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>2096-4129</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1080/20964129.2020.1747946</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Ventilation corridors in cities can decrease air pollution and alleviate heat island problems but there remains a need to fully assess their effectiveness. Few urban managers have been able to take city-scale approaches to the construction of urban ventilation corridors. This study aimed to introduced the Ventilation Corridor Planning (VCP) model, which is a multi-criteria evaluation method combined with a geographical information system (GIS) to determine where the ventilated environment is most appropriate. Specifically, the VCP model took Bozhou, China as the research object and contained two scales, including mesoscale and local scale. In mesoscale scale, we got three outputs to build urban ventilation corridors, including 1) background wind environment, 2) ventilation potential, 3) heat island intensity. In local scale, we used traditional computational fluid dynamics (CFD) model to verify the impact of VCP criteria. The results revealed that compared with the traditional CFD model, the proposed VCP model has advantages in establishing a comprehensive evaluation standard. In addition, the application of VCP model in macro and micro also enhances the efficiency of ventilation corridor construction. Overall, this study introduced a effective modeling method to urban ventilation corridors planning, and provide a way to study the urban climate.</abstract><remote-database-name>Taylor and Francis+NEJM</remote-database-name><urls><web-urls><url>https://doi.org/10.1080/20964129.2020.1747946</url></web-urls><pdf-urls><url>C:\Users\Kuba\Zotero\storage\6XJ8746I\Gu et al. - 2020 - Spatial planning for urban ventilation corridors b.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><access-date>2023-01-17 08:19:55</access-date></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Wong, Man Sing</author><author>Nichol, Janet E.</author><author>To, Pui Hang</author><author>Wang, Jingzhi</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A simple method for designation of urban ventilation corridors and its application to urban heat island analysis</title><secondary-title>Building and Environment</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Building and Environment</full-title><abbr-1>Building and Environment</abbr-1></periodical><pages>1880-1889</pages><volume>45</volume><number>8</number><issue>8</issue><keywords><keyword>Geographic information systems</keyword><keyword>Remote sensing</keyword><keyword>Frontal area index</keyword><keyword>Urban heat island</keyword><keyword>Ventilation path</keyword><keyword>done</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2010</year><pub-dates><date>2010-08-01</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>0360-1323</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.buildenv.2010.02.019</electronic-resource-num><abstract>This paper describes urban wind ventilation mapping, using the concept of “building frontal area index”, and uses the Kowloon peninsula of Hong Kong as an example of a dense, sub-tropical urban environment where ventilation is critical for human health. The frontal area index is calculated for uniform 100 m grid cells, based on three dimensional buildings in each cell, for eight different wind directions. The frontal area index is then correlated with a land use map, and the results indicate that high density commercial and industrial areas with large building footprints had higher values than other urban land use types. Using the map of frontal area index, the main ventilation pathways across the urban area are located using least cost path analysis in a raster GIS. Field measurements of urban winds confirmed the significance and functionality of these modelled ventilation paths. Comparison of the pathways with a map of the urban heat island suggests that ventilation is a key parameter in mitigating heat island formation in the study area. Planning and environmental authorities may use the derived frontal area index and ventilation maps as objective measures of environmental quality within a city, especially when temperatures in the inner city are a major concern.</abstract><remote-database-name>ScienceDirect</remote-database-name><language>en</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0360132310000776</url></web-urls><pdf-urls><url>C:\Users\Kuba\Zotero\storage\GNW2PLSQ\Wong et al. - 2010 - A simple method for designation of urban ventilati.pdf</url></pdf-urls><text-urls><url>C:\Users\Kuba\Zotero\storage\LHUPD326\S0360132310000776.html</url></text-urls></urls><access-date>2023-01-17 08:20:57</access-date></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Xie, Peng</author><author>Yang, Jun</author><author>Wang, Huiying</author><author>Liu, Yanfang</author><author>Liu, Yaolin</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A New method of simulating urban ventilation corridors using circuit theory</title><secondary-title>Sustainable Cities and Society</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Sustainable Cities and Society</full-title><abbr-1>Sustainable Cities and Society</abbr-1></periodical><pages>102162</pages><volume>59</volume><keywords><keyword>Ventilation corridors</keyword><keyword>Circuit theory</keyword><keyword>Graph theory</keyword><keyword>Urban canopy</keyword><keyword>Wuhan</keyword><keyword>done</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2020</year><pub-dates><date>2020-08-01</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>2210-6707</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.scs.2020.102162</electronic-resource-num><abstract>With the continuous development of global urbanization, the urban heat island effect has increasingly become one of the important factors that reduces the quality of urban life. Among the many factors affecting the formation of urban heat islands, urban canopy ventilation is considered to have great potential for improving urban heat islands. Based on the traditional numerical simulation of ventilation corridor analysis, this paper proposes a new approach for ventilation corridor recognition based on circuit theory. The connotations of resistance, current, and voltage in the simulation of urban ventilation environment were explained separately. Taking Wuhan as the research area, local three-dimensional building data were used as the data source, and a simulation experiment of the urban ventilation environment with different winds was carried out on the 100-m grid scale. Unlike the method based on the least-cost path analysis by which only a few main ventilation corridors can be generated, the results of the method proposed in this paper cover all grid cells in the study area. The simulation results were represented by probabilistic values, which can effectively reflect the ventilation corridor and ventilation barriers. In addition to identifying the ventilation corridors, the tuyeres were also well identified.</abstract><remote-database-name>ScienceDirect</remote-database-name><language>en</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2210670720301499</url></web-urls><pdf-urls><url>C:\Users\Kuba\Zotero\storage\L9UJ4FTR\Xie et al. - 2020 - A New method of simulating urban ventilation corri.pdf</url></pdf-urls><text-urls><url>C:\Users\Kuba\Zotero\storage\8R6R4AVS\S2210670720301499.html</url></text-urls></urls><access-date>2023-01-17 08:22:35</access-date></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Fang, Yunhao</author><author>Zhao, Liyuan</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Assessing the environmental benefits of urban ventilation corridors: A case study in Hefei, China</title><secondary-title>Building and Environment</secondary-title><short-title>Assessing the environmental benefits of urban ventilation corridors</short-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Building and Environment</full-title><abbr-1>Building and Environment</abbr-1></periodical><pages>108810</pages><volume>212</volume><keywords><keyword>Environmental benefit</keyword><keyword>Kernel density</keyword><keyword>Least cost path (LCP)</keyword><keyword>Multisource data</keyword><keyword>Urban planning strategy</keyword><keyword>Urban ventilation corridor</keyword><keyword>nie wiem czy adekwatne - do ponownego przeanalizowania</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2022</year><pub-dates><date>2022-03-15</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>0360-1323</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.buildenv.2022.108810</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Precise and timely assessments of the environmental benefits of urban ventilation corridors are important for understanding urban sustainability. Previous studies have mainly focused on the construction of urban ventilation corridors, while less attention has been given to the subsequent environmental benefits that are generated. Taking the main urban area of Hefei as an example, this study proposed a corridor construction model that was based on the ventilation resistance coefficient (VRC) and quantified and compared the environmental indicators for different corridor levels to understand the environmental benefits that were created. Datasets that combined architecture morphology and wind frequency were utilized to construct four-season urban ventilation corridors at a macro level. Three environmental indicators were adopted combined with the VRC model: i) reduction of air pollutant concentrations (PM2.5), ii) reduction of land surface temperatures (LST), and iii) utilization efficiency of vegetation space (NDVI). The results indicated that (1) the VRC that was based on the architecture morphology datasets had a significant correlation with urban environmental benefits, including the PM2.5, LST and NDVI levels. (2) Compared with current project-based ventilation corridors, those constructed by considering the VRC can provide greater environmental benefits. (3) The intersection nodes had higher ventilation benefits than other areas of the ventilation corridors and showed significant spatial aggregation characteristics in alleviating the PM2.5 concentrations and surface temperatures. The method proposed in this study provides important theoretical support for the improved construction of future urban ventilation corridors.</abstract><remote-database-name>ScienceDirect</remote-database-name><language>en</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0360132322000580</url></web-urls><pdf-urls><url>C:\Users\Kuba\Zotero\storage\VWGKVXJT\Fang i Zhao - 2022 - Assessing the environmental benefits of urban vent.pdf</url></pdf-urls><text-urls><url>C:\Users\Kuba\Zotero\storage\GJR8G58M\S0360132322000580.html</url></text-urls></urls><access-date>2023-01-17 08:24:32</access-date></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Wang, Weiwu</author><author>Wang, Di</author><author>Chen, Huan</author><author>Wang, Biyan</author><author>Chen, Xin</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Identifying urban ventilation corridors through quantitative analysis of ventilation potential and wind characteristics</title><secondary-title>Building and Environment</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Building and Environment</full-title><abbr-1>Building and Environment</abbr-1></periodical><pages>108943</pages><volume>214</volume><keywords><keyword>Geographical information system (GIS) spatial analysis</keyword><keyword>Land surface temperature retrieval</keyword><keyword>Urban ventilation corridor (UVC)</keyword><keyword>Ventilation potential</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2022</year><pub-dates><date>2022-04-15</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>0360-1323</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.buildenv.2022.108943</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Urban heat islands (UHIs) are mainly caused by mismanaged urban development. Urban ventilation corridors (UVCs) can effectively reduce UHIs. Hangzhou, a large, dense city in eastern China, is one of the nation's hottest cities and must urgently improve its ventilation. In this study, a newly developed method combining land surface temperature retrieval, GIS spatial analysis, and weather data was employed to design city-level UVCs. The functional space and compensation space of UVCs are identified based on the LandsatETM8 image data inversion of surface temperature. The contribution of affect factors, such as building density, building height, green land area, waterbody, roads, and urban terrain, to the urban ventilation potential is calculated using AHP and GIS. Areas with tremendous ventilation potential were identified as possible ventilation corridors by using an evaluation model and considering wind characteristics. Fifty-four high-temperature zones and 48 low-temperature zones were identified as functional and compensative spaces in Hangzhou, respectively. On the urban scale, green space (area &gt;500ha), water bodies (area &gt;300ha or width &gt;100 m), and roads (width &gt;50 m) were considered to be the factors that have the greatest impact on urban ventilation potential. The LCP method was used to verify the accuracy and rationality of the method proposed in this study to determine the city-scale UVC. UVC planning schemes and construction measures were proposed to provide rich information and a reference basis for the new general land and space planning of Hangzhou. However, to improve the accuracy of the potential ventilation results, the urban underlying surface criteria should be re-evaluated more comprehensively.</abstract><remote-database-name>ScienceDirect</remote-database-name><language>en</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S036013232200186X</url></web-urls><pdf-urls><url>C:\Users\Kuba\Zotero\storage\YZ3G6ZUR\Wang et al. - 2022 - Identifying urban ventilation corridors through qu.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><access-date>2023-01-17 08:26:40</access-date></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Xie, Peng</author><author>Liu, Dianfeng</author><author>Liu, Yanfang</author><author>Liu, Yaolin</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A Least Cumulative Ventilation Cost Method for Urban Ventilation Environment Analysis</title><secondary-title>Complexity</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Complexity</full-title></periodical><pages>e9015923</pages><volume>2020</volume><keywords><keyword>done</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2020</year><pub-dates><date>2020/5/12</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>1076-2787</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1155/2020/9015923</electronic-resource-num><abstract>The correct urban building layout is an important influencing factor in urban ventilation, and the heat island effect has become an important factor affecting the quality of urban life. Optimization of the urban building layout can play a role in mitigating the heat island effect. The traditional ventilation corridor analysis method, based on a least-cost path analysis, can only generate a few main ventilation corridors. It is difficult to obtain global ventilation results covering the whole study area using this method of analysis. On the basis of urban morphology and a least-cost path analysis, this study proposes a “least cumulative ventilation cost” method for analyzing urban ventilation. Taking Wuhan downtown as a research area, the urban ventilation environment under different wind directions and seasons was analyzed. This method can effectively express the ventilation conditions throughout the whole study area and can simultaneously express the quality of the generated corridors effectively. The results show that Wuhan has three levels of ventilation corridor. Moreover, the ventilation conditions in Wuchang (Wuchang, Qingshan, and Hongshan) are better than those in Hankou (Qiaokou, Jianghan, and Jiang’an).</abstract><remote-database-name>www.hindawi.com</remote-database-name><language>en</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.hindawi.com/journals/complexity/2020/9015923/</url></web-urls><pdf-urls><url>https://downloads.hindawi.com/journals/complexity/2020/9015923.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><access-date>2023-01-17 08:27:47</access-date></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Chang, Shouzhi</author><author>Jiang, Qigang</author><author>Zhao, Ying</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Integrating CFD and GIS into the Development of Urban Ventilation Corridors: A Case Study in Changchun City, China</title><secondary-title>Sustainability</secondary-title><short-title>Integrating CFD and GIS into the Development of Urban Ventilation Corridors</short-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Sustainability</full-title></periodical><pages>1814</pages><volume>10</volume><number>6</number><issue>6</issue><keywords><keyword>GIS</keyword><keyword>ventilation corridors</keyword><keyword>CFD</keyword><keyword>Changchun City</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2018</year><pub-dates><date>2018/6</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>2071-1050</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.3390/su10061814</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Given the situation of urban expansion and environmental deterioration, the government and researchers are paying considerable attention to ventilation corridors. The construction of urban ventilation corridors requires quantitative data support. Computational fluid dynamics (CFD) has advantages in the fine assessment of wind environment, and a geographic information system (GIS) has excellent performance in spatial analysis. With Changchun City used as an example, this study proposes the establishment of ventilation corridors on an urban scale to mitigate the urban-heat-island effect, and to accelerate the diffusion of air pollution. CFD simulations provided detailed spatiotemporal characteristics of wind speed and wind direction at various heights. These simulations were useful for identifying potential ventilation corridors. In general, the wind-speed and wind-direction characteristics at a height of 30 m clearly indicated potential ventilation corridors. Potential paths existed in the leading wind and south–north directions. The areas that required improvement were favorably situated in the path of potential ventilation corridors. The main roads, green spaces, and water had good connectivity. A total of five ventilation corridors were constructed, and they will directly affect the poor urban thermal environment, and enhance the mobility of air.</abstract><remote-database-name>www.mdpi.com</remote-database-name><language>en</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.mdpi.com/2071-1050/10/6/1814</url></web-urls><pdf-urls><url>C:\Users\Kuba\Zotero\storage\W53LVV49\Chang et al. - 2018 - Integrating CFD and GIS into the Development of Ur.pdf</url><url>https://www.mdpi.com/2071-1050/10/6/1814/pdf?version=1527752738</url></pdf-urls></urls><access-date>2023-01-17 08:29:01</access-date></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Zheng, Zuofang</author><author>Ren, Guoyu</author><author>Gao, Hua</author><author>Yang, Yuanjian</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Urban ventilation planning and its associated benefits based on numerical experiments: A case study in beijing, China</title><secondary-title>Building and Environment</secondary-title><short-title>Urban ventilation planning and its associated benefits based on numerical experiments</short-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Building and Environment</full-title><abbr-1>Building and Environment</abbr-1></periodical><pages>109383</pages><volume>222</volume><keywords><keyword>Ventilation corridors</keyword><keyword>Beijing</keyword><keyword>Benefit evaluation</keyword><keyword>Climatic-environmental effect</keyword><keyword>Numerical simulation</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2022</year><pub-dates><date>2022-08-15</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>0360-1323</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.buildenv.2022.109383</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Urban ventilation planning (UVP) are critically important to sustainable and green urban development. However, the climatic-environmental effects and benefits of urban ventilation corridors have yet to be fully understood. In this study, high-resolution simulation tests were carried out for winter of 2018 and summer of 2019 using the weather research and forecasting model (WRF) coupled with the urban canopy model (UCM) and the refined surface type and UVP of Beijing City. After the construction of the ventilation corridors, the average temperature in the Beijing urban area can be reduced by 0.18 °C, and the wind speed and relative humidity can be increased by 0.33 m s−1 and 2.83%, respectively. The major contributions of the ventilation corridors to local meteorological elements are the wind speed enhancement-induced advection effect and the improvement of the turbulent flux over urban surface. Further, the cost-benefit analysis of UVP show that the urban heat island intensity (UHII), the average PM2.5 concentration, and the number of days with light or above levels of air pollution will be decreased by 13.7%, 11.7%, and 20.2%, respectively. This implies that, disregarding the reduction of the UHII and its effect, urban ventilation corridor is conducive to improving the winter urban living environment. However, the problems of haze pollution cannot be completely resolved by ventilation corridors alone, and the weakening of the winter UHII in the northern city is a disadvantage to energy-saving and habitat comfort. Our findings provide a reference base for policy decisions and technical guidelines for UVP of high-density cities.</abstract><remote-database-name>ScienceDirect</remote-database-name><language>en</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0360132322006163</url></web-urls><text-urls><url>C:\Users\Kuba\Zotero\storage\II9HSM6L\S0360132322006163.html</url></text-urls></urls><access-date>2023-01-17 08:29:17</access-date></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Peng, Fen</author><author>Wong, Man Sing</author><author>Wan, Yiliang</author><author>Nichol, Janet E.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Modeling of urban wind ventilation using high resolution airborne LiDAR data</title><secondary-title>Computers, Environment and Urban Systems</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Computers, Environment and Urban Systems</full-title><abbr-1>Computers, Environment and Urban Systems</abbr-1></periodical><pages>81-90</pages><volume>64</volume><keywords><keyword>Frontal area index</keyword><keyword>Airborne LiDAR</keyword><keyword>Computer fluid dynamics</keyword><keyword>Least cost path</keyword><keyword>Ventilation corridor</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year><pub-dates><date>2017-07-01</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>0198-9715</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.compenvurbsys.2017.01.003</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Accurate mapping of wind ventilation in an urban environment is challenging when large spatial coverage is required. This study has developed a GIS-based model for estimating the frontal area index (FAI) of buildings, infrastructure, and trees using very high resolution airborne light detection and ranging (LiDAR) data, which can also be used to investigate the “wall effect” caused by high-rise buildings at a finer spatial scale along the coasts in the Kowloon Peninsula of Hong Kong. New algorithms were created by improving previous algorithms utilizing airborne LiDAR data in raster unit, as well as considering the backward flow coefficient between windward and leeward buildings. The ventilation corridors estimated by FAI and least cost path (LCP) analysis were analyzed. The optimal ventilation corridors passing through the Kowloon peninsula were observed in the east-west and west-east directions. In addition, these ventilation paths were validated with a computer fluid dynamics (CFD) model i.e. Airflow Analysis in ESRI. The newly developed model calculates finer FAI with greater accuracy when compared with vector-based building polygons. This model further depicts buildings, infrastructure, and trees which are considered as obstacles to wind ventilation. The results can be used by environmental and planning authorities to identify ventilation corridors, and for scenario analysis in urban redevelopment.</abstract><remote-database-name>ScienceDirect</remote-database-name><language>en</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0198971516301740</url></web-urls><pdf-urls><url>C:\Users\Kuba\Zotero\storage\RWHDNH3K\Peng et al. - 2017 - Modeling of urban wind ventilation using high reso.pdf</url></pdf-urls><text-urls><url>C:\Users\Kuba\Zotero\storage\6UPRMIW6\S0198971516301740.html</url></text-urls></urls><access-date>2023-01-17 08:30:34</access-date></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Su, Na</author><author>Zhou, Dian</author><author>Jiang, Xiaotao</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Study on the Application of Ventilation Corridor Planning in Urban New Area --A Case Study of Xixian New Area</title><secondary-title>Procedia Engineering</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Procedia Engineering</full-title><abbr-1>Procedia Engineering</abbr-1></periodical><pages>340-349</pages><volume>169</volume><keywords><keyword>Planning Method Application</keyword><keyword>Urban New Area</keyword><keyword>Ventilation Corridor</keyword><keyword>XiXian New Area</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year><pub-dates><date>2016-01-01</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>1877-7058</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.proeng.2016.10.042</electronic-resource-num><abstract>The cause of urban heat island effect is closely related to urban activities, urban construction environment and landscape. The planning of urban ventilation corridor in Urban New District focuses on the optimization of the wind environment, not only can effectively improve the quality of living environment, but also can conducive to the realization of energy-saving emission reduction. According to the urban wind air flow movement and urban underlying surface characteristics, the paper takes Xixian New Area as an example, according to the climate in cold regions divided different ecological and climatic zoning, uses CFD simulation method, and determines the city through the main control factors of the location and number of wind corridor, purporting and corridor on the windward side of density control in urban ecology and open space layout, in order to providing a reference for future planning and construction has a good climate and environment in new city.</abstract><remote-database-name>ScienceDirect</remote-database-name><language>en</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1877705816332453</url></web-urls><pdf-urls><url>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1877705816332453/pdf?md5=b3b36b726aee5661f18858226707f056&amp;pid=1-s2.0-S1877705816332453-main.pdf&amp;isDTMRedir=Y</url></pdf-urls><text-urls><url>C:\Users\Kuba\Zotero\storage\VBFUM5Y8\S1877705816332453.html</url></text-urls></urls><access-date>2023-01-17 08:31:31</access-date></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Liu, Dandan</author><author>Zhou, Shenghui</author><author>Wang, Lijun</author><author>Chi, Qian</author><author>Zhu, Mengyao</author><author>Tang, Weichao</author><author>Zhao, Xiao</author><author>Xu, Siqi</author><author>Ye, Siyu</author><author>Lee, Jay</author><author>Cui, Yaoping</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Research on the Planning of an Urban Ventilation Corridor Based on the Urban Underlying Surface Taking Kaifeng City as an Example</title><secondary-title>Land</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Land</full-title></periodical><pages>206</pages><volume>11</volume><number>2</number><issue>2</issue><keywords><keyword>Kaifeng city</keyword><keyword>single-window algorithm</keyword><keyword>urban heat island</keyword><keyword>ventilation corridor</keyword><keyword>done</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2022</year><pub-dates><date>2022/2</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>2073-445X</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.3390/land11020206</electronic-resource-num><abstract>With the rapid development of urbanization, various urban problems such as air pollution, urban heat islands, poor ventilation, and so on have followed. Ventilation corridors can improve the internal ventilation conditions of a city and can effectively alleviate these urban problems. Taking Kaifeng as an example of a medium-sized city, this study used meteorological analysis and remote sensing (RS) technology and a geographical information system (GIS) to plan ventilation corridors. Through analysis of the thermal environment, the influential factors of the underlying surface (building density, road length, water length, vegetation coverage) and wind environment in Kaifeng, the compensation space and action space, and the comprehensive values of the ventilation potential in each region were determined. The results show that with the use of the single-window algorithm and Landsat8 data, high-resolution ground temperature can be retrieved. Moreover, although the ventilation potential value of Kaifeng in the northern part is better than that in the southern part, the temperature in the north is higher than that in the south. Through comparison and analysis of the location of the low-temperature zone, the air duct opening of the ventilation corridor can be determined and the source areas of three ecological ventilation corridors identified. According to the ventilation corridor air duct opening, the urban underlying surface and the dominant wind direction of Kaifeng city, two ventilation corridors located on the eastern and western sides of Kaifeng city were planned. This urban ventilation corridor planning method, which is based on temperature difference analysis and determination of the source area of the ventilation corridor, can provide a reference for the construction of an ecologically livable city.</abstract><remote-database-name>www.mdpi.com</remote-database-name><language>en</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.mdpi.com/2073-445X/11/2/206</url></web-urls><pdf-urls><url>https://www.mdpi.com/2073-445X/11/2/206/pdf?version=1644476845</url><url>C:\Users\Kuba\Zotero\storage\G8QMUY8E\Liu et al. - 2022 - Research on the Planning of an Urban Ventilation C.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><access-date>2023-01-17 08:32:54</access-date></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Qiao, Zhi</author><author>Xu, Xinliang</author><author>Wu, Feng</author><author>Luo, Wen</author><author>Wang, Fang</author><author>Liu, Luo</author><author>Sun, Zongyao</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Urban ventilation network model: A case study of the core zone of capital function in Beijing metropolitan area</title><secondary-title>Journal of Cleaner Production</secondary-title><short-title>Urban ventilation network model</short-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Cleaner Production</full-title><abbr-1>Journal of Cleaner Production</abbr-1></periodical><pages>526-535</pages><volume>168</volume><keywords><keyword>GIS</keyword><keyword>Least cost path</keyword><keyword>Line density</keyword><keyword>Urban ventilation network model</keyword><keyword>Ventilation resistance coefficient</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year><pub-dates><date>2017-12-01</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>0959-6526</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.jclepro.2017.09.006</electronic-resource-num><abstract>China has experienced extreme urban heat island effects and air pollution associated with rapid urbanization. Optimizing urban ventilation environment could relieve these environmental problems. In this study, an Urban Ventilation Network Model (UVNM) was developed to explore the impact of urban morphology and building height on the urban ventilation condition. The study calculated the ventilation resistance coefficient of building height according to fluid mechanics, and then determined the least cost path among the air inlets and outlets considering the direction and frequency of wind. Eventually, corridors at several different levels of ventilation were extracted by classifying the line densities of least cost paths, which were effectively verified through land surface temperature retrieved from the Landsat Thematic Mapper. The new model is more scientific and convenient than traditional urban construction environmental assessment software in terms of data acquisition and hardware support. The results suggest that urban design based on urban morphology and building height and considering the direction and frequency of wind would be effective for optimizing ventilation to regulate urban environmental problems.</abstract><remote-database-name>ScienceDirect</remote-database-name><language>en</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0959652617319935</url></web-urls><pdf-urls><url>C:\Users\Kuba\Zotero\storage\VUWJS5YI\Qiao et al. - 2017 - Urban ventilation network model A case study of t.pdf</url></pdf-urls><text-urls><url>C:\Users\Kuba\Zotero\storage\LZ5K3X6U\S0959652617319935.html</url></text-urls></urls><access-date>2023-01-17 08:33:18</access-date></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Chen, Chaoxiang</author><author>Ye, Shiping</author><author>Bai, Zhican</author><author>Wang, Juan</author><author>Nedzved, Alexander</author><author>Ablameyko, Sergey</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Intelligent Mining of Urban Ventilated Corridor Based on Digital Surface Model under the Guidance of K-Means</title><secondary-title>ISPRS International Journal of Geo-Information</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>ISPRS International Journal of Geo-Information</full-title></periodical><pages>216</pages><volume>11</volume><number>4</number><issue>4</issue><keywords><keyword>DSM</keyword><keyword>frontal area density (FAD)</keyword><keyword>intelligent mining</keyword><keyword>K-means</keyword><keyword>tilt photography</keyword><keyword>urban ventilated corridor</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2022</year><pub-dates><date>2022/4</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>2220-9964</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.3390/ijgi11040216</electronic-resource-num><abstract>With the acceleration of urbanization, climate problems affecting human health and safe operation of cities have intensified, such as heat island effect, haze, and acid rain. Using high-resolution remote sensing mapping image data to design scientific and efficient algorithms to excavate and plan urban ventilation corridors and improve urban ventilation environment is an effective way to solve these problems. In this paper, we use unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV) tilt photography technology to obtain high-precision remote sensing image digital elevation model (DEM) and digital surface model (DSM) data, count the city’s dominant wind direction in each season using long-term meteorological data, and use building height to calculate the dominant wind direction. The projection algorithm calculates the windward area density of this dominant direction. Under the guidance of K-means, the binarized windward area density map is used to determine each area and boundary of potential ventilation corridors within the threshold range, and the length and angle of each area’s fitted elliptical long axis are calculated to extract the ventilation corridors that meet the criteria. On the basis of high-precision stereo remote sensing data from UAV, the paper uses image classification, segmentation, fitting, and fusion algorithms to intelligently mine potential urban ventilation corridors, and the effectiveness of the proposed method is demonstrated through a case study in Zhuji City, Zhejiang Province.</abstract><remote-database-name>www.mdpi.com</remote-database-name><language>en</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.mdpi.com/2220-9964/11/4/216</url></web-urls><pdf-urls><url>C:\Users\Kuba\Zotero\storage\8T6ITSXQ\Chen et al. - 2022 - Intelligent Mining of Urban Ventilated Corridor Ba.pdf</url><url>https://www.mdpi.com/2220-9964/11/4/216/pdf?version=1647951688</url></pdf-urls></urls><access-date>2023-01-17 08:43:18</access-date></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Ng, Edward</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Policies and technical guidelines for urban planning of high-density cities – air ventilation assessment (AVA) of Hong Kong</title><secondary-title>Building and Environment</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Building and Environment</full-title><abbr-1>Building and Environment</abbr-1></periodical><pages>1478-1488</pages><volume>44</volume><number>7</number><issue>7</issue><keywords><keyword>High-density city</keyword><keyword>Human urban thermal comfort</keyword><keyword>Urban planning</keyword><keyword>Urban ventilation</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2009</year><pub-dates><date>2009-07-01</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>0360-1323</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.buildenv.2008.06.013</electronic-resource-num><abstract>In 2003, Hong Kong was hit by severe acute respiratory syndrome (SARS) from which many people died. The Hong Kong Government subsequently set up a Governmental Team Clean Committee to investigate possible urban design policies. Team Clean charged the task to the Planning Department, HKSAR. In 2003, it initiated a study titled: “Feasibility Study for Establishment of Air Ventilation Assessment (AVA) System.” A number of focused studies were conducted. It eventually led to the technical methodology and guidelines of the air ventilation assessment (AVA) system. Unlike many countries with guidelines for dealing with gust wind problems, AVA is a guideline for weak wind conditions specifically designed to deal with congested urban conditions. The AVA system basically establishes a method for project developers to objectively assess their designs. In 2006, the government of Hong Kong officially adopted the system and required all major publicly funded development projects to undertake the assessment. The scientific and implementation processes leading to the AVA system are reported in this paper.</abstract><remote-database-name>ScienceDirect</remote-database-name><language>en</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0360132308001455</url></web-urls><pdf-urls><url>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0360132308001455/pdfft?md5=c3138e1703cfe1d78a1b298b30e3683d&amp;pid=1-s2.0-S0360132308001455-main.pdf&amp;isDTMRedir=Y</url></pdf-urls><text-urls><url>C:\Users\Kuba\Zotero\storage\DR6KSZBL\S0360132308001455.html</url></text-urls></urls><access-date>2023-01-17 08:43:30</access-date></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Conference Proceedings">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Wicht, Marzena</author><author>Wicht, Andreas</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Urban ventilation corridors - performance evaluation using remotely sensed data</title><secondary-title>2017 Joint Urban Remote Sensing Event (JURSE)</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>2017 Joint Urban Remote Sensing Event (JURSE)</full-title></periodical><pages>1-4</pages><keywords><keyword>Buildings</keyword><keyword>Planning</keyword><keyword>Urban areas</keyword><keyword>Ventilation</keyword><keyword>Indexes</keyword><keyword>Vegetation mapping</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year><pub-dates><date>2017-03</date></pub-dates></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/JURSE.2017.7924539</electronic-resource-num><abstract>This paper describes detection and evaluation of urban ventilation corridors and uses Warsaw as an example of dense, temperate - zone urban environment. The potential ventilation corridors are derived based on the roughness parameters mapping in three different epochs: 1992, 2002, 2011 and later compared to the designed and law-protected areas, which in theory, should form the system of ventilation and air exchange in Warsaw. These three years have been chosen based on the time when spatial planning law was introduced and different local zoning plans for Warsaw were passed, including preserved areas for the ventilation corridors. The roughness parameters mapping focuses mainly on frontal area index calculation and itis based on the building database partially derived from satellite imagery (SPOT). Comparison of the derived corridors with the officially planned preservation areas suggests inaccuracies in their extent, identifies obstacles that occurred over almost twenty years and calls for an evaluation. The proposed analysis might be used by local authorities to revise the shape of existing corridors and to recognise problematic areas, which could lead to better spatial management.</abstract><remote-database-name>IEEE Xplore</remote-database-name><urls><text-urls><url>C:\Users\Kuba\Zotero\storage\JXZMW8C6\7924539.html</url></text-urls></urls><custom3>2017 Joint Urban Remote Sensing Event (JURSE)</custom3></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Suder, Arkadiusz</author><author>Szymanowski, Mariusz</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Determination of Ventilation Channels In Urban Area: A Case Study of Wrocław (Poland)</title><secondary-title>Pure and Applied Geophysics</secondary-title><short-title>Determination of Ventilation Channels In Urban Area</short-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Pure and Applied Geophysics</full-title><abbr-1>Pure Appl. Geophys.</abbr-1></periodical><pages>965-975</pages><volume>171</volume><number>6</number><issue>6</issue><keywords><keyword>roughness parameters</keyword><keyword>Morphometry</keyword><keyword>ventilation paths and channels</keyword><keyword>Wrocław</keyword><keyword>done</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2014</year><pub-dates><date>2014-06-01</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>1420-9136</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1007/s00024-013-0659-9</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Urban areas are among the roughest landscapes in the Earth and its aerodynamical properties are responsible for a lot of processes and phenomena of urban climate, such as surface drag and pollutant dispersion. These properties can be quantitatively expressed by various parameters, with zero plane displacement height (zd) and roughness length (z0) as the most frequently applied. Based on remotely gathered (LIDAR scan) height data and morphometric methods of roughness calculations, the comprehensive procedure to determine ventilation channels in urban area is proposed and implemented on the example from Wrocław, Poland. Morphometric analysis of urban structure allowed establishing a proper database of aerodynamic parameters of the city. Then a series of maps of the city showing the distribution of two roughness parameters were prepared. GIS tools were used to carry out the analysis of roughness data, assuming various directions of wind flow. It enabled to determine the locations of potential ventilation paths in the city which, if combined, form large ventilation channels. They may have a significant role in improving air quality and be a valuable source of information for local government responsible for the appropriate development of the city.</abstract><remote-database-name>Springer Link</remote-database-name><language>en</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00024-013-0659-9</url></web-urls><pdf-urls><url>C:\Users\Kuba\Zotero\storage\K8A5VJ55\2Suder i Szymanowski - 2014 - Determination of Ventilation Channels In Urban Are.pdf</url><url>https://link.springer.com/content/pdf/10.1007%2Fs00024-013-0659-9.pdf</url><url>C:\Users\Kuba\Zotero\storage\YKZLLFAL\Suder i Szymanowski - 2014 - Determination of Ventilation Channels In Urban Are.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><access-date>2023-01-17 09:00:04</access-date></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Gál, T.</author><author>Unger, J.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Detection of ventilation paths using high-resolution roughness parameter mapping in a large urban area</title><secondary-title>Building and Environment</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Building and Environment</full-title><abbr-1>Building and Environment</abbr-1></periodical><pages>198-206</pages><volume>44</volume><number>1</number><issue>1</issue><keywords><keyword>3D building database</keyword><keyword>Displacement height</keyword><keyword>Frontal area</keyword><keyword>Porosity</keyword><keyword>Roughness length</keyword><keyword>Urban roughness mapping</keyword><keyword>done</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2009</year><pub-dates><date>2009-01-01</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>0360-1323</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.buildenv.2008.02.008</electronic-resource-num><abstract>In this study, an urban roughness mapping method is presented on the example of a large study area in Szeged, Hungary, as an example. With this roughness mapping procedure, the potential ventilation paths of the city can be located. Our calculations of the roughness parameters are based on a 3D building database; however, this new approach using the lot area polygons provides more detailed results than other recent studies. The detected ventilation paths could play a significant role in the development of the urban heat island circulation and result in the reduction of air pollution in the central parts of the city. Based on our results, we can mark out the areas where the city government should keep the advantages of the ventilation paths considering the human comfort aspects of the urban climate, thus providing important input data for urban planning procedures.</abstract><remote-database-name>ScienceDirect</remote-database-name><language>en</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0360132308000322</url></web-urls><pdf-urls><url>C:\Users\Kuba\Zotero\storage\SSP9EIQ4\Gál i Unger - 2009 - Detection of ventilation paths using high-resoluti.pdf</url></pdf-urls><text-urls><url>C:\Users\Kuba\Zotero\storage\SF6FWWWE\S0360132308000322.html</url></text-urls></urls><access-date>2023-01-25 15:31:23</access-date></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Eldesoky, A. H. M.</author><author>Colaninno, N.</author><author>Morello, E.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>MAPPING URBAN VENTILATION CORRIDORS AND ASSESSING THEIR IMPACT UPON THE COOLING EFFECT OF GREENING SOLUTIONS</title><secondary-title>The International Archives of the Photogrammetry, Remote Sensing and Spatial Information Sciences</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>The International Archives of the Photogrammetry, Remote Sensing and Spatial Information Sciences</full-title><abbr-1>Int. Arch. Photogramm. Remote Sens. Spatial Inf. Sci.</abbr-1></periodical><pages>665-672</pages><volume>XLIII-B4-2020</volume><keywords><keyword>done</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2020</year><pub-dates><date>2020-08-25</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>2194-9034</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.5194/isprs-archives-XLIII-B4-2020-665-2020</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Abstract. Over the past decades, climate change has become among the top issues challenging cities worldwide, endangering the urban infrastructures and threatening the health of millions of people. Hence, climate action, both in terms of mitigation and adaptation to climate change, has become a priority for urban planning. This work introduces an example of the promising role that spatial analysis and statistical modelling, employing Geographical Information Systems (GIS) and freely available satellite and land-based data, can provide in supporting urban climate design and policymaking. In particular, this study puts special attention on the Urban Heat Island (UHI) phenomenon. Here, we first introduce a simple, but effective morphological-based approach for mapping potential ventilation corridors across cities of uniform built-up structure, as a common UHI mitigation measure. Then, we propose a methodology for assessing the relative role of these corridors in maximizing the impacts of green solutions upon lowering high temperature. Results show that even under very calm wind conditions, there is still an opportunity for maximizing the benefits of greening measures on the urban climate. Also, it has been demonstrated that green ventilation corridors are more effective during night-time when the UHI effect is peaked. The research findings are very promising, especially for cities where wind is a marginal potentiality.</abstract><remote-database-name>Semantic Scholar</remote-database-name><language>en</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.int-arch-photogramm-remote-sens-spatial-inf-sci.net/XLIII-B4-2020/665/2020/</url></web-urls><pdf-urls><url>C:\Users\Kuba\Zotero\storage\7J34ILU8\Eldesoky et al. - 2020 - MAPPING URBAN VENTILATION CORRIDORS AND ASSESSING .pdf</url></pdf-urls><text-urls><url>https://www.semanticscholar.org/paper/MAPPING-URBAN-VENTILATION-CORRIDORS-AND-ASSESSING-Eldesoky-Colaninno/7715fe8062a2c1080921bd4223f6ac03a72ca97b</url></text-urls></urls><access-date>2023-02-02 11:41:59</access-date></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Web Page">12</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Fo, Ma</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Determining the direction of polygons?</title><secondary-title>Geographic Information Systems Stack Exchange</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Geographic Information Systems Stack Exchange</full-title></periodical><dates><year>2017</year><pub-dates><date>2017-03-28</date></pub-dates></dates><work-type>Forum post</work-type><urls><web-urls><url>https://gis.stackexchange.com/q/233771</url></web-urls><text-urls><url>C:\Users\Kuba\Zotero\storage\6H6EASIQ\determining-the-direction-of-polygons.html</url></text-urls></urls><access-date>2023-02-02 13:22:31</access-date><misc2>Forum post</misc2></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Web Page">12</ref-type><titles><title>Studium uwarunkowań i kierunków zagospodarowania przestrzennego Warszawy</title></titles><dates><year>2023</year><pub-dates><date>2023-02-02</date></pub-dates></dates><abstract>Studium jest dokumentem planistycznym określającym politykę zagospodarowania przestrzennego gminy (miasta) dla jej całego obszaru.Studium jest dokumentem planistycznym określającym politykę zagospodarowania przestrzennego gminy (miasta) dla jej całego obszaru.</abstract><language>pl-PL</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://architektura.um.warszawa.pl/-/studium-uwarunkowan-i-kierunkow-zagospodarowania-przestrzennego-warszawy</url></web-urls></urls><access-date>2023-02-02 23:40:09</access-date></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Yang, Jun</author><author>Wang, Yichen</author><author>Xiao, Xiangming</author><author>Jin, Cui</author><author>Xia, Jianhong (Cecilia)</author><author>Li, Xueming</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Spatial differentiation of urban wind and thermal environment in different grid sizes</title><secondary-title>Urban Climate</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Urban Climate</full-title><abbr-1>Urban Climate</abbr-1></periodical><pages>100458</pages><volume>28</volume><keywords><keyword>Frontal area index</keyword><keyword>Dalian city</keyword><keyword>Grid size</keyword><keyword>Maximum mutual information</keyword><keyword>Urban thermal environment</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2019</year><pub-dates><date>2019-06-01</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>2212-0955</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.uclim.2019.100458</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Due to rapid urbanization, China's urban morphology has undergone tremendous changes, resulting in an increased urban heat island (UHI) effect and negative impact of thermal environment, especially in summer. Studying the scale effect between urban wind and thermal environment can provide the best scale for the wind environment planning on mitigating UHI effect. Taking Dalian as an example, using multi-source data, a nonlinear correlation analysis was used to analyze the correlation between the frontal area index (FAI) and land 77uuyyhsurface temperature (LST) under different grids. The results show that first, FAI is sensitive to grid-size changes. When the grid size increases from 25 × 25 m to 150 × 150 m with a step size of 25 m, in July, the numbers of grids with FAI &gt; 1 are 19,992, 1538, 153, 20, 4, and 0 (0%) accounting for 2.106%, 0.645%, 0.081%, 0.019%, 0.006%, and 0% of the total, respectively. In September, the numbers of grids with FAI &gt; 1 are 17,633, 1643, 164, 22, 8, and 0, accounting for 1.849%, 0.689%, 0.155%, 0.037%, 0.021%, and 0% of the total, respectively. When the grid size is greater than or equal to 150 × 150 m, there is no grid with FAI &gt; 1. Second, the most effective grid size to study the relationship between FAI and LST is 25 m. When the grid size increases from 25 m to 300 m with a step size of 25 m, the correlation between FAI and LST shows a significant decrease. When the grid size is 25 m, the correlation is the strongest.</abstract><remote-database-name>ScienceDirect</remote-database-name><language>en</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2212095518302785</url></web-urls><pdf-urls><url>C:\Users\Kuba\Zotero\storage\C4YB7H7I\Yang et al. - 2019 - Spatial differentiation of urban wind and thermal .pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><access-date>2023-02-04 23:23:29</access-date></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Web Page">12</ref-type><titles><title>Construction of Ventilation Corridors and Smog Control in Beijing</title></titles><dates/><language>en</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.worldscientific.com/doi/epdf/10.1142/S2345748117500166</url></web-urls><pdf-urls><url>C:\Users\Kuba\Zotero\storage\RN497EW9\Construction of Ventilation Corridors and Smog Con.pdf</url></pdf-urls><text-urls><url>C:\Users\Kuba\Zotero\storage\ENDGYZRD\S2345748117500166.html</url></text-urls></urls><access-date>2023-02-07 13:02:18</access-date></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Liu, Weiling</author><author>Zhang, Guo</author><author>Jiang, Yonghua</author><author>Wang, Jingyin</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Effective Range and Driving Factors of the Urban Ventilation Corridor Effect on Urban Thermal Comfort at Unified Scale with Multisource Data</title><secondary-title>Remote Sensing</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Remote Sensing</full-title></periodical><pages>1783</pages><volume>13</volume><number>9</number><issue>9</issue><keywords><keyword>frontal area index</keyword><keyword>the Pearl River Delta</keyword><keyword>thermal comfort</keyword><keyword>urban ventilation corridor</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2021</year><pub-dates><date>2021/1</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>2072-4292</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.3390/rs13091783</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Urban ventilation corridors serve as channels of fresh air flow between the city and suburbs, helping to improve the wind and thermal environments and thermal comfort. However, owing to the limited number of weather stations, it is impossible to quantitatively reveal the effective effect range of urban ventilation corridors on urban thermal comfort at the scale of 100 × 100 m, which is optimal for urban ventilation corridors. In this study, we integrated building data, the European Centre for Medium-Range weather forecast data (ECMWF), MOD13Q1, and other multisource data to analyse the effect of urban ventilation corridors on urban thermal comfort at a unified scale of 100 × 100 m. The results showed that ECMWF and Landsat8 data could be used as substitute factors to improve the universal thermal climate index (UTCI) urban spatial resolution. The effective range of urban ventilation corridor effects on the urban surface temperature and urban comfort was ≤1000 m, with building density and vegetation coverage as the main factors limiting this range. Therefore, attention should be paid to the effective range of urban ventilation corridors, the surrounding building density, vegetation coverage, and the rational use of urban ventilation corridors to reduce the energy consumption of air conditioning in summer.</abstract><remote-database-name>www.mdpi.com</remote-database-name><language>en</language><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.mdpi.com/2072-4292/13/9/1783</url></web-urls><pdf-urls><url>C:\Users\Kuba\Zotero\storage\2CDB8QVZ\Liu et al. - 2021 - Effective Range and Driving Factors of the Urban V.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><access-date>2023-02-11 14:25:42</access-date></record><record><database name="MyLibrary">MyLibrary</database><source-app name="Zotero">Zotero</source-app><ref-type name="Journal Article">17</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Wicht, Marzena</author><author>Wicht, Andreas</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>LiDAR-Based Approach for Urban Ventilation Corridors Mapping</title><secondary-title>IEEE Journal of Selected Topics in Applied Earth Observations and Remote Sensing</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>IEEE Journal of Selected Topics in Applied Earth Observations and Remote Sensing</full-title></periodical><pages>2742-2751</pages><volume>11</volume><number>8</number><issue>8</issue><keywords><keyword>roughness parameters</keyword><keyword>Air pollution</keyword><keyword>Computational modeling</keyword><keyword>Drag coefficient for vegetation</keyword><keyword>light detection and ranging (LiDAR)</keyword><keyword>morphometric methods</keyword><keyword>Urban areas</keyword><keyword>urban ventilation corridors</keyword><keyword>Ventilation</keyword><keyword>Wind speed</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2018</year><pub-dates><date>2018-08</date></pub-dates></dates><isbn>2151-1535</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/JSTARS.2018.2791410</electronic-resource-num><abstract>Cities, recognized as one of the roughest surfaces, significantly reduce wind velocity. This leads to a greater concentration of pollution and increased temperature in urban areas. A proper urban design may promote the air flow and mitigate these negative phenomena. This paper describes a novel approach to detect and analyze the potential urban ventilation corridors. The concept is based on the morphometric analyses, where roughness parameters (such as roughness length and displacement height), as well as porosity are investigated as opposed to previous studies. Commonly available light detection and ranging (LiDAR) data enable more detailed terrain study, as the topography and obstacle features (type, dimensions, and porosity) might be investigated. In comparison to the previous studies and long adapted practices, this approach takes advantage of all information incorporated in LiDAR data to deliver even more accurate results. The comparison of the detected corridors, with the officially designed corridors in our study area in Warsaw, suggests inaccuracies in their extent (only 40% of their areas might still be functioning) and calls for an evaluation. The results deliver areas that may be recognized as urban ventilation corridors and serve as air regeneration and ventilation system. They may also be used for developing new solutions for continuously evolving cities.</abstract><remote-database-name>IEEE Xplore</remote-database-name><urls><pdf-urls><url>C:\Users\Kuba\Zotero\storage\9HEF96BH\Wicht i Wicht - 2018 - LiDAR-Based Approach for Urban Ventilation Corrido.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record></records></xml>